Guide to the William Somerset Maugham collection, 1921-1979 (inclusive), 1921-1958 (bulk) M0013
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- 1954, 14 letters (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 4. Cap Ferrat, [1954] April 5; ALS 1 1/2pp. + envelope
    Finances, houseguests, travel plans, N.Y. lawyers (royalties).
  - 5. Cap Ferrat, [1954] June 11; ALS 1p. + envelope
    Returned from trip, going to London, Turkey, Greece, Liza.
  - 6. Cap Ferrat, [1954] August 5; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Letter inserted Formerly 13/1/16
    Thanks, faimily, correcting new book, finances.
  - 7. Cap Ferrat, [1954] September 5; ALS 2pp. [envelope dated September 4]
    Going to Spain with Alan, new book.
  - 8. Granada, [1954 September 29]; Postcard
    Weather.
  - 9. London (The Dorchester), [1954] October 29; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Birthday present, health.
  - 10. London, [1954] November 23; ALS 4pp.
  - 11. London (The Dorchester), [1954] November 28; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Ill health, going to the Riviera, Alan, Authors' Society Fudn, tax, Winston's [Churchill?] birthday.
  - 12., [1954] December 9 (envelope dated December 8); ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Fund, health, thanks, Gerald Kelly.
  - 13. London (The Dorchester), [1954] December 13; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Health, weather, Liza.
- 1955, (21 letters) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1. Cap Ferrat, [1955] January 13; ALS 2 1/4pp.
    Finances, thanks.
  - 2. Cap Ferrat Mabel Alanson, [1955] January 25; ALS 1 1/4pp.
    Birthday, thanks, BA's visit.
  - 3. Cap Ferrat, [1955] January 30; ALS 1p.
    BA left.
  - 4. Cap Ferrat, [1955] February 7; ALS 1 1/8pp. + envelope
    [BA]'s trip home, thanks.
  - 5. Cap Ferrat, [1955] February 21; ALS 1p. + envelope
  - 6. Cap Ferrat, 1955 April 8; ALS 2pp.
    Agreements, Trust Deed, Alan (?).
  - 7. Cap Ferrat, [1955] April 22; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Prince of Monaco's wedding.
  - 8. Cap Ferrat, [1955] July 1; ALS 1p. + envelope
    Consolation for Mabel's health.
  - 9. Cap Ferrat Mabel [Alanson], 1955 July 16; 1 1/2pp. + envelope
    Memories of [WSM] meeting Mabel.
  - 10. Cap Ferrat, [1955] July 28; ALS 1 1/2pp. + envelope [dated July 27]
    Going to Salzburg, Liza's mother died, Robin.
  - 11. Cap Ferrat, 1955 August 4; ALS 2pp.
    Sympathy for Mabel's death, WSM invites BA to visit.
  - 12. Cap Ferrat, [1955 August 25]; ALS 1p. + envelope
    Thanks for photos.
  - 13. Cap Ferrat, 1955 September [25]; AN 1p. + envelope [dated September 25]
    BA's visit.
  - 14. Cap Ferrat, [1955] September 30 MISDATED!; ALS 2pp.
    Finances, Gerald Kelly, thanks, lunched with Winston [Churchill], T.V. agreement with Ronald Coleman.
  - 15. London (The Dorchester), [1955] October 7; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Thanks for whiskey from BA, BA's visit.
  - 16. London (The Dorchester), [1955] October 8; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Thansk, [WSM]'s brother.
  - 17. London (The Dorchester), [1955] October 30; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Earthquakes in S.F., Princess Margaret, thanks.
  - 18. London (The Dorchester), [1955] November 7; ALS 1 1/2pp. + envelope
    Asks BA not to send anymore foodstuffs, [WSM] sending detective story to BA.
  - 19. London (The Dorchester), 1955 November 22; ALS 1 1/2pp. + envelope
    Terry Tipkin(?), sending BA reprint of something written 50 years earlier, Rubenstein.
  - 20. London AS to BA [?], 1955 December 13; TL (not signed) 2pp.
    Gerald Kelly, “Moon and Sixpence”, Honor Earl.
  - 21. Cap Ferrat, [1955] December 18; 2pp. + envelope
    Renting villa to Butler, Chancellor of the Exchequer, sale of WSM's mss. at auction by Gerald Kelly.
  - 22. Cap Ferrat, [1955] December 29; ALS 1 1/2pp.
    WSM's neice, Author's Society Fund, Dick Simon?.
- 1956, (17 letters) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1. Cairo (Semiramis Hotel), 1956 January 15; ALS 2pp. + envelope (envelope dated January '55)
    Going to Assoan as guests of Aga Khan?
  - 2. Assouan (Cataract Hotel), [1956] January 22; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Finances, trust to Nick & Camilla, Aga Khan.
  - 3. Cairo (Semiramis Hotel), [1956] January 28; ALS 3 1/2pp.
    Trip up the Nile.
  - 4. Cap Ferrat, [1956] February 10; ALS 1 1/2pp. + envelope
    Health, Finances.
  - 5. Cap Ferrat, [1956] February 19; ALS
  - 6. Cap Ferrat, [1956] March 13; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Health (ear), garden.
  - 7. Cap Ferrat, [1956] May 16; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Alan ill, new car, 500th performance of play in Paris, Royalties.
  - 8. Abano, [1956] June 6; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    BA going to Europe.
  - 9. Cap Ferrat, [1956] July 8; ALS 1 1/2pp. + envelope (dated 11 July)
    Work, first son-in-law.
  - 10. Cap Ferrat, [1956] August 4; ALS 1 1/4pp. + envelope dated August 5
    Gerald and Jane Kelly to visit.
  - 11. Cap Ferrat, [1956] August 29; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Liza & Camilla (her daughter), Gerald & Jane Kelly, going to London, party at Monte Carlo, Princess Grace.
  - 12. Cap Ferrat, [1956] September 7; ALS 1 1/2pp. + envelope
    BA to visit, Kelly's visit, Ellen Doubleday to visit, finances (Gerald Kelly).
  - 13. London, 1956 October 16; Telegram 1p. + envelope
    WSM worried because he hadn't heard from BA.
  - 14. London (The Dorchester), [1956] October 21; ALS 1 1/2pp. + envelope
    Relieved to hear from BA, thanks for masks, health.
  - 15. London (The Dorchester), [1956] November 2; ALS 2 1/2pp. + envelope
    Public appearances, Egypt situation, Labour Party, Alan, raise (?) finances.
  - 16. London (The Dorchester), [1956] November 25; ALS 1 1/2pp. + envelope
    Health, finances, returning to Cap Ferrat, gas rationing.
  - 17. Cap Ferrat, [1956] December 17; ALS 2pp. [No envelope]
    Thanks, gas & oil shortage, lunch with Lady Bateman (?).
  - 18. Cap Ferrat WSM and Alan to BA, [1956] December 31; Telegram 1p.
    Happy New Year & Love.
- 1957, (21 letters) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1. Cap Ferrat, 1957 January 9; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Finances, Alan's trust, BA's birthday.
  - 2. Cap Ferrat, [1957] January 23; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Age [Maugham & Alanson], girl born to Princess Grace, finances, provisions for Alan.
  - 3. Cap Ferrat, [1957] January 28; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Thanks for birthday card, death of Bob [Tarkion?], “Elsie's” husband; TV interview.
  - 4. Cap Ferrat, [1957] February 4; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Glad [BA] gave MS to University, “Rain”, location of [WSM]'s MSS in Universities & libraries, The Moon & Sixpence, heating & weather.
  - 5. Cap Ferrat, [1957] February 5; ALS 2pp. + envelope [dated February 8?]
    Finances, funds for Alan, Liza, Author's Society, fuel oil.
  - 6. Cap Ferrat, [1957] March 9; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Health, thanks for photographs, Prof. Swank, trust fund, [WSM] gve Liza money to buy house, grandchildren.
  - 7. Cap Ferrat, [1957] March 24; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    S.F. earthquake, health, letter from Doug Black.
  - 8. Cap Ferrat, [1957] April 19; ALS 1 1/2pp. + envelope
    Health, planned holiday to Germany & Austria.
  - 9. Heidelberg, [1957 May 14]; Autographed Postcard Signed
  - 10. Austria, Bad Gastein (Grand Hotel De L'Europe), [1957]? May 29; ALS 1p.
    [WSM] sat for German sculptor, health.
  - 11. Cap Ferrat, [1957]? June 1
    [NO: OUT OF ORDER]
    Mabel's health (Mabel already died!!!)
  - 12. Badgastein, [1957 June 7]; Autograph Postcard Signed
    Health: “cure”.
  - 13. Cap Ferrat, [1957] July 8; ALS 1 1/2pp. + envelope
    Weather, work.
  - 14. Cap Ferrat, [1957] July 26; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Work, Riviera crowded, Rubenstein.
  - 15. Cap Ferrat, [1957] September 1; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Alanson's health, work on [WSM's] last book, wages rose.
  - 16. Cap Ferrat, [1957] September 26; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Father [Lacomb?]
  - 17. London (The Dorchester), [1957] October 20; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Stocks, Chales [Gorin]?, bridge player “Elsie”.
  - 18. London (The Dorchester), [1957] November 27; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    President's stroke.
  - 19. London (The Dorchester), [1957] December 4
    WSM sending print to BA.
  - 20. Postcard from Madrid [OUT OF ORDER], [1957] Misdated
  - 21. 18, Half Moon St., Mayfair W.I., ND
    Note [OUT OF ORDER]
- 1958, 11 letters (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1. Cap Ferrat, 1958 January 1; ALS 1 1/2pp. + envelope
    Holiday parties.
  - 2. Cap Ferrat, 1958 January 5; Telegram 1p.
    Birthday thoughts.
  - 3. Cap Ferrat, [1958] January 10; ALS 1 1/2pp.
    Finances, trust, Author's Society Fund.
  - 4., 1958 [?]; Envelope
  - 5. Cap Ferrat, [1958] January 19; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Finances, bought picture.
  - 6. Cap Ferrat, [1958] January 25; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Thanks for birthday carnations, Guaranty Trust letter.
  - 7. New York to Cap Ferrat Guaranty Trust Co. of N.Y. to WSM, 1958 January 20; TLS 2pp. + envelope
    G.T.Co. asks WSM to put his holdings in their charge. [WSM sent this letter to BA in S.F. in cover dated February 8, 1958.]
  - 8. Cap Ferrat, [1958] February 6; ALS 2pp.
    BA's health, WSM's reply to Guaranty Trust Co., thanks.
  - 9. Cap Ferrat, [1958] February 25; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Letter from G. T. Co., WSM declines invitation to U. S., work on last book, Doug [Black].
  - 10. Cap Ferrat, 1958 March 22; Telegram 1p. + envelope
    WSM wants news of BA.
  - 11. Cap Ferrat, [1958 April 4]; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Thanks for cable, Doug Black, [WSM's] brother died.
  - 12. Venezia WSM & Alan to BA, 1958 April 25; Telegram 1p. + envelope
    Sympathy.
  - 13. Venezia (Gritti Palace-Hotel), [1958] April 25; ALS 1 1/8pp. + envelope
    Sympathy--BA's brother died.
  - 14. Vevey (Suisse) (Hotel Des Trois-Couronnes), [1958?] May 17; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Health, WSM leaving clinic, invites BA to Cap Ferrat.
- No Years Given, 17 letters (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1. 5, Portland Place, W.1., [1935-40]; ALS 2pp.
    Agreements, Lawrence [Sharpe], finances, Robin, war.
  - 2. Cap Ferrat, [?] February 12; ALS 2pp.
    Finances, taxes, new book, “Gerald”, work.
  - 3. Hotel Tivoli, Ancon, [?] February 7; ALS 3 1/2pp.
    Sailing to Los Angeles, wants to visit BA, Mabel.
  - 4. Delhi, Maiden's Hotel, [1938] March 15; ALS 4pp. + envelope
    Finances, India, Robin, Robins's father Lord Chancellor, book success, Theatre, Doubleday
    Moved to 13/1/3 1st Item (Item 0)
  - 5. Cap Ferrat, [?] April 10; ALS 2pp.
    Thanks, Annette, Alan: salary, Author's Society Fund, Robin, finances, houseguests, Labour Movement, prize money, Liza's divorce.
  - 6. Cap Ferrat, [ca. 1940] May 7; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Finances, soldiers, possibility of war, work.
    moved to 13/1/3
  - 7. Vichy, Carlton Majestic Thermal, [?] June 9; ALS 2pp.
    Taxes, finances, inheritance, “cure”, houseguests, business & stocks.
  - 8. Cap Ferrat, [ca. 1954] June 27; ALS 2pp.
    Work, Queen to deliver insignia, Arthur Rubinstein.
    moved to 13/1/11
  - 9. Cap Ferrat, [?] July 3; ALS 2pp.
    Finances, Theatre, comments on trip to Sweden, Denmark, Belgium.
  - 10. Cap Ferrat, [?] July 17; ALS 2pp.
    Thanks, houseguests, Liza's wedding (second).
  - 11. Cap Ferrat, [1952] July 23; ALS 1p.
    Health, clinic in Geneva, Alan.
    moved to 13/1/9
  - 12. Cap Ferrat, [?] July 31; ALS 2pp. + envelope
    Kelleys, financial markets.
  - 13. envelope addressed to BA, S.F.
  - 14. Cap Ferrat, [?] August 21; ALS 1 1/2pp.
    Thanks, proposed trip to U.S., John & Liza, Princess Alexandria & [?], parties, book.
  - 15. envelope addressed to BA, S.F., [193?]
  - 16. Naples, [?] August 23; ALS 2pp.
    Liza & John, travel, Riviera.
  - 17. Cap Ferrat, [?] August 20; ALS 2pp.
    New novel, Andrew Mellon.
  - 18. Cap Ferrat, [?] September 15; ALS 2pp.
    Work, New York, play, Gerald.
  - 19. Taormina (Hotel Timeo), [?] September 30; ALS 2pp.
    Travels, election in England, Labour Party, Prime Minister.
  - 20. London (The Dorchester), [1954] November 23; ALS 4pp. + envelope
    Interviews, lectures, Encore, Fren? WSM's publisher, election, John, politics, finances.
  - 21. London (The Dorchester), [?] October 28; ALS 2pp.
    Securities, trusts, Guaranty Trust.
  - 22. Spain, Santader, Autograph Postcard Signed
    [Comillas?]
  - 23., [[1940]?] August 19; ALS 2pp.
    Work, travel to U.S., Gerald, war, villa, Churchill.
  - 24. Spain?, Postcard
  - 25. 4 envelopes.
- holograph preface with signed typescript copy. Signed typescript of address given to Royal Academy of Art., Six ALSs (Box 2, Folder [A])
  moved to 13/3/6
  - 1. [OUT OF ORDER] Cap Ferrat WSM to “Mr. [J. Terry] Bender”, 1958 April 1; TLS 1p. (1)
    Cover letter sending “Preface”.
  - 2. [OUT OF ORDER] Cap Ferrat WSM to JT[Bender], 1958 March 16; TLS 1p. (1)
    “I should like to write a short piece for your exhibition.”
  - 3. Printed preface from the Stanford keepsake, 1958 May; 2pp. (4)
  - 4. By Way of Preface”, 1958 May “; Typescript signed 3pp. (3).
  - 5. “By Way of Preface”, AMsS 3pp. (3).
  - 6. Cap Ferrat WSM to JB, Stanford, 1958 June 10; TLS 1p. (1).
    Stanford exhibit, Alanson's death.
  - 7. Cap Ferrat WSM to Professor Swank, Stanford, 1958 June 12
    “I cannot imagine that my letters to Bertram Alanson could be of any interest to anyone else, and the idea that they might be useful to scholars makes me laugh...I am resigned to being completely forgotten five years after my death.”
  - 8. Cap Ferrat WSM to Ben Abramson, 1938 August 22; TLS 1p. + envelope
    Will not sell twin Mss of Of Human Bondage.
  - 9. WSM to [Royal Academy], 1957; TMsS with holograph corrections 5pp. (5)
    “Response to a toast to literature.”
- Bob [?] to Alanson, 1950-1954; 19 letters (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1. Canterbury [Bob] to BA, 1950 March 24; ALS 4pp. (4) + envelope
    Thanks.
  - 2. Canterbury [Bob] to BA, 1950 April 3; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Presents, household.
  - 3. Canterbury Bob to BA, 1950 April 6 & 7; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Parcels, gratitude, plum puddings.
  - 4. Canterbury [Bob] to “Dear Alansons”, 1950 September 19; ALS 4pp. (4) + envelope
    Weather, Paris, Alan, new film Trio.
  - 5. Monte Carlo Bob to BA, 1950 September 30; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Arrival, King of Egypt.
  - 6. Canterbury Bob and Elsie to BA, 1950 December 5; ALS 2pp. (3) + envelope
    Willie and Alan have never written, Truman and Atlee.
  - 7. Canterbury Bob and Elsie to Alansons, 1951 July 2; ALS 4pp. (4) + envelope
    Xmas puddings, American tourists, trouble getting house maids, Elsie leaving, garden.
  - 8. London Bob to BA, 1952 January 24; ALS 1 1/2pp. (2)
    Birthday, “I shall be 65 on Saturday”, has written a short story for Willie's birthday.
  - 9. Canterbury Bob and Elsie to BA, 1952 July 29; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Health
  - 10. Canterbury Bob to BA, 1953 January 13; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    New cigarette “Dunhill selling well.
  - 11. Canterbury Bob to Alansons, 1952 July 1; ALS 3 1/4pp. (4) + envelope
    Fruit farm, not good financially, Willie not well, Swiss doctors, trip to New York.
  - 12. Canterbury Bob to Alansons, 1953 January 27; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    69th birthday, “dunhill”.
  - 13. Canterbury [Bob] to BA, 1954 May 6; 1p. (1) + envelope
    Some seed packets destroyed.
  - 14. London Bob to BA, 1956 March 14; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Willie back from Egypt, does not look or feel well.
  - 15. Canterbury Bob to BA, 1956 April 3; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Garden and visitors, business letter.
  - 16. Canterbury Bob to BA, 1956 October 30; ALS 1p. + envelope
    Packet of seeds.
  - 17. Monte Carlo [Hotel de Paris?] Bob to BA, [1956] Sunday; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Meeting.
  - 18. Monte Carlo Elsie to BA, [1957 February 19]; APC S
    “Willie looks younger than ever...”
  - 19. Canterbury Elsie to BA, 1957 April 6; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Death of Bob.
- Klaus Jonas to Alanson, 1950-1957; 7 letters (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1. New Brunswick, N.J. KWJ to BA, 1950 August 22; TLS 1p. (1)
    Jonas' bibliography of Maugham's works, mentions a number of authors who have submitted essays on Maugham for one of Jonas' works.
  - 2. New Brunswick, N.J. KWJ to BA, 1953 June 10; ALS 2pp.
    Jonas' writing and lectures on Maugham, Alanson ill, note on Thomas Mann and Hermann Hesse.
  - 3. New Brunswick, N.J. KWJ to BA, 1954 January 18; ALS 2pp. (2)
    The Maugham Enigma, Jonas' tribute to Maugham on Maugham's 80th birthday, Alanson's assistance on KWJ's first literary effort in U.S.
  - 4. New Haven, Connecticut KWJ to BA, 1956 August 5; TLS 2 pp. (2) + envelope
    Center for Maugham Studies, 1958 ALA meeting in S.F.
  - 5. New Haven, Connecticut KWJ to BA, 1956 August 15; ALS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Death of Mrs. Alanson.
  - 6. Pittsburg KWJ to BA, 1957 October 8; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Visited Maugham, planning new works on Maugham, Maugham being considered for Nobel.
  - 7. Pittsburg KWJ to BA, 1957 October 16; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Thanks for advice on buying securities, publication and radio broadcast of KWJ's first visit to Villa Mauresque, “Stanford's Maugham Celebration”.
- Sir Gerald Kelly to Alanson, 1928-1956; 15 letters (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1. Cap Ferrat Gerald [Kelly] to BA, 1928 August 6; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Gambling, Willie rehearsing new play, Kelly translating a Bourdet play.
  - 2. Los Angeles GK to BA, 1941 June 11; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Kelly's house and garden.
  - 3. London GK to BA, 1951 April 3; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope (dated April 1)
    Thanks for food, has a lot of Maugham portraits, pictures painted for pleasure, Alan Searle.
  - 4. London GK to BA, 1952 January 11; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Maugham in England, Royal Academy exhibits.
  - 5. London GK to BA, 1952 March 1; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Food packages, late king.
  - 6. London GK to BA, 1952 October 24; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Portrait of Willie.
  - 7. London GK to BA, 1952 November 29; TLS 1p. (1)
    Frame for portrait and a 1p. sketch of frame in cross-cut with ms notes.
  - 8. London GK to BA, 1953 January 31; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Wants to send money to a friend.
  - 9. London GK to BA, 1953 March 3; TLS 1p. (1)
    Dinner with the Queen, Royal Academy collections.
  - 10. London GK to BA, 1953 October 6; TLS 1p. (1)
    Parcel of bacon, storms.
  - 11. London GK to BA, 1954 December 6; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Health, Willie had fallen and injured himself, Royal Academy dinner.
  - 12. London GK to BA, 1954 December 30; TLS 1p. (2)
    Thanks for parcel.
  - 13. London GK to BA, 1955 February 9; TLS 1p. (2)
    Past President of Royal Academy.
  - 14. London GK to BA, 1956 October 12; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Mutual visit to Willie, art exhibits, wild rice.
  - 15. London GK to BA, 1956 November 2; TLS 2pp. (3) + envelope
    Willie at Dorchester, politics, A. Eden.
- Alan Searle to Alanson, 1939-1954; 27 letters (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1. Hollywood AS to BA, 1939 August 23; ALS 1 1/2pp. (2) + envelope
    Thank you note.
  - 2. London AS to BA, 1939 October 24; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    London in war time, Ashenden.
  - 3. New York AS to BA, 1946; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    A function in Washington.
  - 4. New York AS to BA, 1946 May 9; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    “Willie...more social than Mr. Truman”...
  - 5, Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1947 August 21; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    “Willie...more social than Mr. Truman...”
  - 6. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1947 December 17; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Entertaining the Windsors and some Indian princes, grandchildren, Creatures of Circumstance doing well.
  - 7. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1948 June 20; TLS 2pp. (2)
    Delighted with mocassins, visit to Spain.
  - 8. Vichy AS to BA, 1949 June 18; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Health, WSM has finished editing his notebooks.
  - 9. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1950 January 12; TLS 1p. (1)
    Health, age, travel plans.
  - 10. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1950 March 8; TLS 1p. (1)
    Macombers, Canasta, [Goelet's] wives.
  - 11. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1951 July 14; TLS 1p. (1)
    (see box 2, folder “A”)
    Sends copy (not enclosed) of WSM's speech at the Academy Banquet, health.
  - 12. Vaud AS to BA, 1952 May 7; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
  - 13. Amsterdam AS to BA, 1952 June 2; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
  - 14. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1952 June 20; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Alanson's health.
  - 15. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1952 July 7; TLS 1p. (1)
    Alanson's health, photograph of jaunt to Oxford.
  - 16. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1952 July 12; TLS 1p. (1)
    WSM not well.
  - 17. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1952 July 15; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    WSM's health.
  - 18. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1952 July 28; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    WSM much better.
  - 19. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1952 July 23; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    WSM continues to improve.
  - 20. Lausanne AS to BA, 1952 July 31; TLS 2pp. (2)
  - 21. Lausanne AS to BA, 1952 August 20; TLS 2pp. (2)
  - 22. Lausanne AS to BA, 1952 August 28; TLS 2pp. (2)
    Sutherland's portrait of “Willie”.
  - 23. Lausanne AS to BA, 1952 October 8; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    WSM recovered from operation.
  - 24. London AS to BA, 1952 December 4; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    WSM recovered, social whirl and difficulties.
  - 25. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1953 January 29; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    AS's health.
  - 26 Paris AS to BA, 1954 January 1; TLS 2pp. (2)
    London, WSM's birthday.
  - 27. London AS to BA, 1954 November 4; TLS 2pp. (2)
    WSM's schedule, successful new novel, “Theatre” made into a very successful French play.
- Alan Searle to Alanson, 1955-1958; 26 letters (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1. Salzberg AS to BA, 1955 February 8; TLS 1p. (2) + envelope
    Willie's health and spirits.
  - 2. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1955 March 2; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Inquires about Mabel's health, storm destroyed garden.
  - 3. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1955 March 31; TLS 1 1/2pp (2) + envelope
    Mabel's health, King Macomber.
  - 4. Salzburg AS to BA, 1955 March 31; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Mabel's death.
  - 5. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1955 September 24; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
  - 6. London AS to BA, 1955 October 7; TLS 1p. (1)
    Willie being pestered by the press, etc., death of King Macomber.
  - 7. London AS to BA, 1955 November 30; ALS 1 1/2pp. (2) + envelope
    Searle's health, Rubenstein concerts, going to Egypt.
  - 8. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1956 March 10; TLS 1 1/2pp. (2) + envelope
    Willie ill but getting better.
  - 9. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1956 May 6; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Paris, 500th performance of “Adorable Julia” Willie's health, new car, Richard Adler wants to make a musical of a WSM story.
  - 10. Luxor AS to BA, 1956 February 4; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Egypt, “Guests of the Aga and Beguhr”.
  - 11. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1956 July 18; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Italian trip, financial business.
  - 12. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1956 August 6; TLS 1 1/2pp. (2)
    Photographs of Mabel Alanson. Ellen Doubleday.
  - 13. London AS to BA, 1956 November 11
    Appollo Magazine, health.
  - 14. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1956 December 20; TLS 2pp. (2)
    Christmas greetings.
  - 15. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1957 January 11; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Bob Tritton, musical of Of Human Bondage.
  - 16. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1957 March 27; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Concerned over report of earth tremors in S.F. asthma.
  - 17. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1957 April 29; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Planning trip to Geneva et al, Heidelberg University.
  - 18. Bad Gastein AS to BA, 1957 June 11; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Exhausting time of it with the Press, Sadler's Well's production of The Moon and Sixpence.
  - 19. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1957 August 7; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Klaus Jonas.
  - 20. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1957 August 22; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Have not heard from BA.
  - 21. London AS to BA, 1957 November 1; TLS 1 1/2pp. (2) + envelope
    Still no word from Alanson.
  - 22. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1958 January 10; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Birthday, dinner with Prince Rainer and Princess Grace, “She has improved the prince beyond all recognition”.